JAVIER HERNÁN TORRES URBINA

jav.torresu@gmail.com | +56930249980 https://www.linkedin.com/in/javier-torres-urbina/

INTRODUCTION

I am a computer engineer with experience in agile methodologies. I always strive to present my perspective objectively, thus facilitating informed decision-making and achieving an optimal result. Since I discovered React.js, I have loved designing websites with this library, and in my free time, I enjoy programming for fun.

EDUCATION

Duoc UC Professional Institute of the Catholic University, Chile	Computer and Telecommunications Engineering	2019 - 2022 (Graduated)
Commercial High School Talagante, Chile, Chile	High school education	2015 - 2018
Javiera Carrera Verdugo School D- 118, Chile	Primary education	2007 - 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

INNOVACIONES	Y DESARROLLOS
TECNOLÓGICO	S UPBIRK SPA -
Full-Stack Dev	eloper Junior

My main responsibilities were:

Apr 2023 - Aug 2023

Front-end development using React to generate components in the views, supported by Material UI in the styling process.

Back-end development using Node.js + Express.js for building REST APIs.

Experience using PostgreSQL with the Knex.js ORM to manage migrations, seeds, and SQL queries in the project.

Participation in the development process using the AGILE methodology in collaboration with the IT team.

Coventa S.A - Collection Executive

My positions within Coventa S.A. were:

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

Customer service through phone calls Support and allocation of complaints Management of the collections area Organization and reception of sales

LANGUAGES

English (Advanced). German (basic). Spanish (Native).

SKILLS

JavaScript. MySQL. Html. SCSS. Php. Linux. SQL Server. Git. Node.js. Machine Learning. Angular. React. CSS. PostgreSQL. Bootstrap. Amazon Web Services (AWS). Docker. Knex.js. Express.js. Python. TypeScript. Mongo DB. Redux. Material UI. Scrum.